旧京山港口
起来  站起来啊
Get up! Get up!
获胜者是
The winner,
将对手完全压制住的
by total annihilation,
山哥
Yama!
下一个是谁
Who is next?
谁有种进来挑战小山哥
Who has the guts to step into the ring with little Yama?
山哥
Yama!
我能试试吗
Can I try?
我有个机器人  自己做的
I have a robot. I built it myself.
来吧  小子
Beat it, kid.
本店规矩  先付钱后上场
House rules. You gotta pay to play.
这些够吗
Is this enough?
你叫什么  小家伙
What's your name, little boy?
宏  滨田宏[与英雄同音]
Hiro. Hiro Hamada.
机器人准备  零蛋君
Prepare your bot, zero.
两个机器人上场
Two bots enter,
只有一个能离开
one bot leaves.
选手准备
Fighters ready?
开始
Fight!
刚刚是我第一次比赛  能再试一次吗
That was my first fight. I... Can I try again?
输不起就别玩  小家伙
No one likes a sore loser, little boy.
回去吧
Go home.
我还有钱
I've got more money.
选手准备
Fighters ready?
开始
Fight!
无敌机器人  毁灭模式
Mega-bot, destroy.
什么
What?
-小山哥没有啦  -但是  怎么
- No more little Yama. - But, wha...
这不可能
This is not possible!
我也不敢相信
Hey, I'm as surprised as you are.
新手运气好呗
Beginner's luck.
想再来一局吗  山哥
Do you want to go again, Yama?
没人能从山哥这诓钱
No one hustles Yama!
给他点教训
Teach him a lesson.
伙计们  我们谈谈好吗
Hey, fellas. Let's talk about this.
-宏  上车  -正
- Hiro! Get on! - Tadashi!
来得真是时候
Good timing!
我的妈啊
Oh, mama!
-你没事吧  -没事
- Are you okay? - Yeah.
-你受伤了吗  -没有
- Are you hurt? - No.
那你是脑子进水了吗  傻瓜
Then what were you thinking, knucklehead?
你十三岁就高中毕业
You graduated high school when you were 13,
你就成天干这个
and this is what you're doing?
他们在这
There they are!
抓紧了
Hold on!
好棒
Yes!
回来
Get back here.
机器人竞技是违法的
Bot fighting is illegal.
你会害自己进监狱的
You're going to get yourself arrested.
机器人竞技不违法
Bot fighting is not illegal.
拿来赌钱  那才是违法的
Betting on bot fighting, that's... that's illegal.
但收益颇丰
But so lucrative!
哥哥  我现在鸿运当头  势不可挡啊
I'm on a roll, big brother! And there is no stopping me!
不好
Oh, no.
警局
凯斯婶婶
Hi, Aunt Cass.
你们没事吧  告诉我你们没事
Are you guys okay? Tell me you're okay.
-我们没事  -我们很好
- We're fine. - We're okay.
那就好
Oh, good.
那你们两个傻瓜是脑子进水了吗
Then what were you two knuckleheads thinking?
十年了
For 10 years,
我已经尽全力把你俩拉扯大
I have done the best I could to raise you.
我是个完美的家长吗  不是
Have I been perfect? No.
我了解小孩吗  不了解
Do I know anything about children? No.
我该买本如何教育子女的书吗
Should I have picked up a book on parenting?
或许该买本了
Probably!
我想说什么来着
Where was I going with this? I had a point.
-对不起  -我们爱你  凯斯婶婶
- Sorry. - We love you, Aunt Cass.
我也爱你们
Well, I love you, too!
因为你俩我今天不得不提前打烊
I had to close up early because of you two felons.
在垮掉一代诗歌之夜
On beat poetry night.
化压力为食欲  都怪你俩
Stress eating. Because of you.
来吧  摩奇
Come on, Mochi.
真的好好吃
This is really good!
你最好在凯斯婶婶把咖啡厅吃空之前
You better make this up to Aunt Cass
赶紧弥补过错
before she eats everything in the cafe.
那必须
For sure.
但愿你吸取教训了  笨蛋
And I hope you learned your lesson, bonehead.
当然了
Absolutely.
你要去机器人竞技是不是
You're going bot fighting, aren't you?
就在城市另一边  现在报名还能赶上
There's a fight across town. If I book, I can still make it.
你什么时候
When are you gonna
才能把你的脑袋瓜用在正地方
start doing something with that big brain of yours?
什么  跟你一样去上大学吗
What? Go to college like you?
这样别人就能教我已经知道的东西了吗
So people can tell me stuff I already know?
难以置信
Unbelievable.
爸爸妈妈会怎么说你
What would mom and dad say?
我不知道
I don't know.
他们已经不在了
They're gone.
我三岁他们就去世了  记得吗
They died when I was three, remember?
-我带你去  -真的吗
- I'll take you. - Really?
反正我也拦不住你
I can't stop you from going,
但我也不能让你一个人去
but I'm not going to let you go on your own.
好极了
Sweet.
旧京山理工学院
我们到你的书呆学校来干嘛
What are we doing at your nerd school?
机器人竞技是在那边
Bot-fight's that way!
伊藤石岗机器人学实验室
得拿点东西
Gotta grab something.
要很久吗
Is this gonna take long?
放松  别抱怨啦  马上就好
Relax, you big baby. We'll be in and out.
再说你也没见过我的实验室
Anyway, you've never seen my lab.
好极了  能看到你的书呆子实验室
Oh, great, I get to see your nerd lab!
小心
Heads up!
电磁悬浮吗
Electro-mag suspension?
-你是谁  -我是...
- Who are you? - I'm...
速美子  这是我弟弟宏
Go go, this is my brother Hiro.
欢迎来到书呆实验室
Welcome to the nerd lab.
是啊
Yeah.
我从来没见过电磁悬浮用于单车上
I've never seen electro-mag suspension on a bike before.
零摩擦  单车更快
Zero resistance, faster bike.
但还不够快
But, not fast enough,
目前来说
yet.
别动  请站到线后面去
Do not move. Behind the line, please.
山葵  这是我弟弟宏
Hey, Wasabi. This is my brother Hiro.
你好  宏  准备好大开眼界
Hello, Hiro. Prepare to be amazed.
接着
Catch.
-激光诱导等离子体  -没错
- Laser-induced plasma? - Oh, yeah.
只要一点磁约束就能有超高精密度
With a little magnetic confinement for ultra-precision.
这么乱怎么找东西
Wow. How do you find anything in this mess?
我有系统化摆放
I have a system.
每一件都有自己的位置
There's a place for everything,
一切都是有序的
and everything in its place.
-借我这个  -别这样啊
- Need this! - You can't do that!
这样就无序了  社会需要秩序啊
This is anarchy! Society has rules!
抱歉
Excuse me!
借过一下
Coming through!
正
Tadashi!
老天  你就是宏了吧
Oh, my gosh. You must be Hiro!
我听过你很多事
I've heard so much about you!
时间刚好  时间刚好
Perfect timing. Perfect timing.
好多碳化钨啊
That's a whole lot of tungsten carbide.
足足400磅
400 pounds of it!
过来  过来
Come here, come here, come here.
你会喜欢这个的
You're going to love this.
掺点高氯酸  一滴钴颜料
A dash of perchloric acid, a smidge of cobalt,
一丁点过氧化氢
a hint of hydrogen peroxide,
加热至500开氏度
super-heated to 500 Kelvin, and...
完成啦  有没有很棒
Ta-da! It's pretty great, huh?
很粉红
It's so pink.
最精彩的部分到了
Here's the best part.
很赞是不是
I know, right?
化学金属脆化
Chemical metal embrittlement.
不错啊  柠蜜
Not bad, Honey Lemon.
"柠蜜"  "速美子"  "山葵"
"Honey Lemon"? "Go go"? "Wasabi"?
我就把山葵洒在衣服上一次
I spill wasabi on my shirt one time, people.
就一次
One time!
绰号都是弗雷迪取的
Fred is the one who comes up with the nicknames.
弗雷迪是谁
Who's Fred?
就是我  在这
This guy, right here!
别害怕  只是道具服而已
Don't be alarmed. It is just a suit.
我真人不长这样
This is not my real face and body.
在下大名弗雷迪
The name's Fred.
白天是学校吉祥物  但到了晚上
School mascot by day, but by night,
我还是学校吉祥物
I am also a school mascot.
你什么专业的
So, what's your major?
不  不  我不是学生
No, no, no, I'm not a student.
但我是个狂热科学爱好者
But I am a major science enthusiast.
我想让小蜜给我研制个分子式
I've been trying to get Honey to develop a formula,
能让我变成一个喷火大蜥蜴  想变就变
that can turn me into a fire-breathing lizard at will.
但她说这"不是科学"
But she says that's "Not science."
真的不是
It's really not.
那我猜我让山葵
Yeah, and I guess the shrink ray
帮我研究的缩小射线也不是"科学"咯
I asked Wasabi for isn't "Science" either.
-是吗  -不是
- Is it? - Nope.
好吧  那"隐形三明治"呢
Well, then, what about "Invisible sandwich"?
-宏  -试想一下  你在吃三明治
- Hiro. - Imagine eating a sandwich,
但所有人都觉得你疯了
but everybody just thinks you're crazy.
打住吧
Just stop.
-镭射眼呢  -什么
- Laser eyes? - What?
-痛感手指呢  -别做梦了
- Tingly fingers? - Never gonna happen.
那生长血清呢
Hey, what about a growth serum?
那你在研究什么
So, what have you been working on?
马上给你看
I'll show you.
布基胶带吗
Duct tape?
很不想泼你冷水  哥们
I hate to break it to you, bro.
但已经有人发明了
Already been invented.
老兄
Dude!
好痛
Ow!
这就是我的研究项目
This is what I've been working on.
你好  我叫白球恩
Hello. I am Baymax.
你的个人医疗保健伙伴
Your personal healthcare companion.
我注意到你说"好痛"
I was alerted to the need
表示你需要医疗护理
for medical attention when you said, "Ow."
机器人护士
A robotic nurse.
请用一级到十级表示你现在的疼痛等级
On a scale of 1 to 10, how would you rate your pain?
生理上还是心理上的疼痛
Physical or emotional?
现在我将扫描你
I will scan you now.
扫描完毕
Scan complete.
你的小臂上有轻度表皮擦伤
You have a slight epidermal abrasion on your forearm.
建议使用抗菌喷雾
I suggest an anti-bacterial spray.
喷雾里的具体成分有什么
What's in the spray, specifically?
主要成分是杆菌肽
The primary ingredient is Bacitracin.
真不巧  我对那个过敏
That's a bummer. I'm actually allergic to that.
你并不对杆菌肽过敏
You are not allergic to bacitracin.
倒是对花生有轻度过敏
You do have a mild allergy to peanuts.
不错嘛
Not bad.
你给这家伙编程下了不少功夫啊
You've done some serious coding on this thing, huh?
给他编设了超过一万种医疗措施
Programed him with over 10,000 medical procedures.
滨田正
有了这个芯片才能叫他白求恩
This chip is what makes Baymax, Baymax.
乙烯树脂吗
Vinyl?
想设计成无害友善的东西
Yeah, going for a non-threatening, huggable kind of thing.
看着像个会走路的棉花糖
Looks like a walking marshmallow.
-无意冒犯  -我是个机器人
- No offense. - I am a robot.
不会被冒犯
I cannot be offended.
-高光谱相机吗  -没错
- Hyperspectral cameras? -Yep.
-钛合金支架吗  -碳纤维
- Titanium skeleton? - Carbon fiber.
对  这样更轻
Right. Even lighter.
超强制动机  你都是从哪搞到这些的
Killer actuators. Where did you get those?
都是实验室里研制出来的
Machined them right here, in-house.
-真的吗  -没错
- Really? - Yup.
他能举起一千磅的重物[450公斤]
He can lift 1,000 pounds.
不是吧
Shut up.
你表现得很好  给你个棒棒糖
You have been a good boy. Have a lollipop.
真好
Nice.
在你没对我的服务表示满意之前
I cannot deactivate until you say
我无法进入休眠
you are satisfied with your care.
那好  我对你的服务表示满意
Well then, I'm satisfied with my care.
他能帮助很多人
He's going to help a lot of people.
他用的是什么电池
Hey, what kind of battery does it use?
锂电池
Lithium ion.
超级电容器充电更快
You know, supercapacitors would charge way faster.
又在点灯熬油啦  滨田先生
Burning the midnight oil, Mr. Hamada?
你好  教授
Hey, Professor.
我正准备收工呢
Actually, I was just finishing up.
你就是宏了吧
You must be Hiro.
机器人竞技者  是吧
Bot-fighter, right?
我女儿小时候也喜欢这个
When my daughter was younger, that's all she wanted to do.
我能看看吗
May I?
当然
Sure.
磁轴承伺服系统
Magnetic-bearing servos.
很厉害吧
Pretty sick, huh?
想看看我是怎么把它组装起来的吗
Wanna see how I put 'em together?
大天才
Hey, genius!
这是他发明的
He invented them.
你就是罗伯特·卡拉翰吗
You're Robert Callaghan?
就是
Like, as in,
卡拉翰样条函数
the Callaghan-catmull spline,
和卡拉翰"机器人学定律"的那个卡拉翰吗
and Callaghan's "Laws of robotics"?
没错
That's right.
想过申请这所学校吗
Ever think about applying here?
年龄不是问题
Your age wouldn't be an issue.
我不知道
I don't know.
他可是一门心思投身机器人竞技事业呢
He's pretty serious about his career in bot-fighting.
也没特别当回事
Well, kind of serious.
能看出来
I can see why.
你的机器人获胜肯定小菜一碟
With your bot, winning must come easy.
是吧
Yeah, I guess.
你要喜欢简单的事物
Well, if you like things easy,
我的专业就不适合你
then my program isn't for you.
我们在这里是为了突破机器人学的极限
We push the boundaries of robotics here.
我的学生都将塑造未来
My students go on to shape the future.
很高兴认识你  宏
Nice to meet you, Hiro.
祝你旗开得胜
Good luck with the bot-fights.
你要还想竞技就得赶紧了
We gotta hurry if you want to catch that bot-fight.
我一定要上这里
I have to go here.
要是我不上这个书呆学校
If I don't go to this nerd school,
我会疯的
I'm gonna lose my mind.
我怎么才能被录取
How do I get in?
旧京山理工学院作品展
每年学校都会举行学生作品展示
Every year, the school has a student showcase.
你要是能想出让卡拉翰瞠目的作品
You come up with something that blows Callaghan away,
就能进了
you're in.
但作品一定要很厉害
But, it's gotta be great.
旧京山理工学院作品展
相信我
Trust me.
肯定会
It will be.
一片空白
Nothing!
什么灵感都没有  没用的渣大脑
No ideas! Useless, empty brain!
十四岁就自暴自弃了
Wow. Washed up at 14.
真可悲
So sad.
什么都想不到  完了  肯定进不去了
I got nothing! I'm done. I'm never getting in.
我才不会放弃你呢
Hey, I'm not giving up on you.
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
摇摆一下
Shake things up.
用你聪明的大脑找出方法
Use that big brain of yours to think your way out.
-什么  -换个新角度
- What? - Look for a new angle.
今天这里有很多新玩意儿啊
Wow, a lot of sweet tech here today.
感觉怎么样
How are you feeling?
你是在跟前机器人竞技者说话呢
You're talking to an ex-bot fighter.
要比这更厉害才能让我紧张
Takes a lot more than this to rattle me.
他确实紧张
Yep, he's nervous.
没什么好害怕的  小家伙
You have nothing to fear, little fellow.
-他好紧张  -不  我没有
- He's so tense. - No, I'm not.
放松些  宏
Relax, Hiro.
你的作品很棒  对吧  速美子
Your tech is amazing. Tell him, Go go.
别发牢骚了  拿出点气概
Stop whining. Woman up.
我没事
I'm fine!
小伙  你需要什么  除臭剂  薄荷糖
What do you need, little man? Deodorant? Breath mint?
新内裤
Fresh pair of underpants?
内裤吗  你真的需要些特殊帮助
Underpants? You need serious help.
我是有备而来
Hey, I come prepared.
我六个月都没洗过衣服了
I haven't done laundry in six months.
一条内裤能穿四天
One pair lasts me four days.
正面穿完反面穿
I go front, I go back,
脏了翻面还能穿
I go inside-out. Then I go front and back.
那真是又恶心又棒极了
Wow. That is both disgusting and awesome.
别鼓励他了
Don't encourage him.
这叫做"循环利用"
It's called "Recycling."
下一个展示者  滨田宏
Next presenter, Hiro Hamada.
太好了  到你了
Oh, yeah. This is it.
我想我该上场了
I guess I'm up.
快来拍照  大家一起说"宏"
Okay, photo, photo! Everybody say, "Hiro."
-宏  -太棒了
- Hiro! - Yeah!
我们爱你  宏  祝你好运
We love you, Hiro. Good luck!
-别搞砸了  -祝好运  小伙
- Don't mess it up. - Break a leg, little man.
科学  太棒了
Science, yeah!
好了  伙计  该上场了
All right, bro. This is it.
快来  别不理我呀
Come on. Don't leave me hanging.
怎么了
What's going on?
我真的很想来这里上学
I really want to go here.
你能行的
You got this.
我是宏...
My name is Hiro...
对不起
Sorry.
我叫滨田宏
My name is Hiro Hamada,
我做了些我觉得非常酷的东西
and I've been working on something that I think is pretty cool.
希望你们会喜欢
I hope you like it.
这是一个微型机器人
This is a microbot.
深呼吸
Breathe.
看起来很不起眼
It doesn't look like much,
但当它跟其它同伴连在一起的时候
but when it links up with the rest of its pals,
事情就会变得有趣起来
things get a little more interesting.
微型机器人都由这个神经传递器来控制
The microbots are controlled with this neural transmitter.
我想让它们做什么
I think what I want them to do...
他们就会做什么
They do it.
这个技术能应用于无限领域
The applications for this tech are limitless.
建筑物
Construction.
过去需要团队手工合作
What used to take teams of people working by hand
几个月或者几年的工程
for months or years,
现在只需要一个人就能完成
can now be accomplished by one person.
而这还只是个开始
And that's just the beginning.
交通应用怎么样
How about transportation?
微型机器人可以轻松将任何东西移动到
Microbots can move anything anywhere,
任何地方
with ease.
只要你能想到  微型机器人就能做到
If you can think it, the microbots can do it.
唯一的局限就是你的想象力
The only limit is your imagination.
微型机器人
Microbots!
那是我的外甥
That's my nephew!
太棒了
Yes!
我的家人  我爱我的家人
My family! I love my family!
太棒了
Nailed it!
-你做到了  -不错嘛
- You did it! - Not bad!
真令我大开眼界  伙计
Yeah! You just blew my mind, dude!
他们很爱你  太了不起了
They loved you. That was amazing!
是的
Yes.
再开发一下  你的技术会是革命性的
With some development, your tech could be revolutionary.
阿里斯特·克瑞
Alistair Krei!
我能看一下吗
May I?
真了不起
Extraordinary.
我想要你的微型机器人加入克瑞科技
I want your microbots at Krei Tech.
不会吧
Shut up.
克瑞先生说的对
Mr. Krei is right.
你的微型机器人是一项创新技术
Your microbots are an inspired piece of tech.
你可以继续开发它们
You can continue to develop them,
或者将它们卖给
or you can sell them to a man
一个完全自私自利的人
who's only guided by his own self-interest.
罗伯特  我知道你是怎么看我的
Robert, I know how you feel about me,
但那不应该影响到...
but it shouldn't affect...
这是你的决定  宏
This is your decision, Hiro.
但你应该知道
But you should know
克瑞先生习惯于走捷径并忽视可靠的科学
Mr. Krei has cut corners and ignored sound science
以达到自己的目的
to get where he is.
那不是真的
That's just not true.
对克瑞科技持有你的微型机器人
I wouldn't trust Krei Tech
或是任何东西
with your microbots,
我表示不信任
or anything else.
宏  我会给你
Hiro, I'm offering you
任何十四岁少年都无法想象的金钱
more money than any 14-year-old could imagine.
很感谢你的邀请  克瑞先生
I appreciate the offer, Mr. Krei,
但它们不出售
but they're not for sale.
我以为你会做出明智的决定
I thought you were smarter than that.
罗伯特
Robert.
克瑞先生
Mr. Krei.
那是我弟弟的
That's my brother's.
是啊
That's right.
很期待在课堂上见到你
I look forward to seeing you in class.
太不可思议了
Unbelievable!
我就说过嘛
That's what I'm talking about.
好了  天才们
All right, geniuses,
让我们填饱饥饿的大脑吧
let's feed those hungry brains.
回餐馆去
Back to the cafe!
晚饭我请客
Dinner is on me!
太棒了  没什么比免费的食物更好了
Yes! Nothing is better than free food!
-凯斯婶婶  -除非是发霉的
- Aunt Cass? - Unless it's moldy.
我们稍后就到  好吗
We'll... we'll catch up, okay?
当然  我太为你骄傲了
Sure. I'm so proud of you.
你们两个都是
Both of you.
谢谢  凯斯婶婶
Thanks, Aunt Cass.
我知道你要说什么
I know what you're going to say.
我应该为自己感到骄傲
"I should be proud of myself,"
因为我终于用天赋做了些重要的事
"because I'm finally using my gift for something important."
没有没有  我只是想说
No, no. I was just gonna
你的飞行是整个展示的低潮
tell you your fly was down for the whole show.
哈哈  太搞笑了
Ha-ha-hilarious.
你说什么
What?
欢迎来书呆学校  书呆子
Welcome to nerd school, nerd.
我...
Hey, I...
要不是你  我也不会在这里  所以
I wouldn't be here if it wasn't for you. So,
你懂的
you know,
非常感谢你没有放弃我
thanks for not giving up on me.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
是的  我没事
Yeah. I'm okay.
但是卡拉翰教授还在里面
But Professor Callaghan is still in there.
正  不要
Tadashi, no!
卡拉翰在里面
Callaghan's in there.
得有人去帮忙
Someone has to help.
正
Tadashi!
给  喝点茶
Here. Have some tea.
亲爱的
Hey, sweetie.
凯斯婶婶
Hey, Aunt Cass.
松田女士在餐厅里
Mrs. Matsuda's in the cafe.
穿了件完全不适合80岁老人穿的衣服
She's wearing something super inappropriate for an 80-year-old.
说这个总能把你逗笑
That always cracks you up.
你该下楼来
You should come down.
晚会儿吧
Maybe later.
学校又打电话来了
The university called again.
已经开课几周了
It's been a few weeks since classes started.
但他们说现在去注册还不晚
But they said it's not too late to register.
好的  谢谢  我会考虑的
Okay. Thanks. I'll think about it.
机器人竞技
嘿  宏
Hey, Hiro.
我们只是想看看你怎么样了
We just wanted to check in, and see how you're doing.
我们希望你能在这里  伙计
We wish you were here, buddy.
宏  如果我现在能拥有一项超能力
Hiro, if I could have only one superpower right now,
我希望是能从摄像头里爬出去
it would be the ability to crawl through this camera,
给你一个大大的拥抱
and give you a big hug.
好痛
Ow!
你好  我是白球恩
Hello. I am Baymax,
你的个人医疗保健伙伴
your personal healthcare companion.
白球恩
Hey, Baymax.
我不知道你还能工作
I didn't know you were still active.
我感受到了伤感的情绪
I heard a sound of distress.
有什么麻烦事吗
What seems to be the trouble?
我只是不小心踢到脚趾头
I just stubbed my toe a little.
我没事
I'm fine.
请用一级到十级来表示你的疼痛等级
On a scale of 1 to 10, how would you rate your pain?
零级  我没事  真的
A zero. I'm okay, really.
谢谢  你可以缩回去了
Thanks. You can shrink now.
我要碰一下会疼吗
Does it hurt when I touch it?
没事儿的  你别碰
That's okay. No touching.
我很好
I'm fine...
你摔倒了
You have fallen.
你以为呢
You think?
-以一级到...  -好痛
- On a scale of 1 to... - Ow!
以一级...
On a scale...
On a sca...
以一级到十级...
On a scale of 1 to 10...
请用一级到十级来表示你的疼痛等级
On a scale of 1 to 10, how would you rate your pain?
零级
Zero.
-你可以哭出来  -不  不
- It is all right to cry. - No. No, no, no, no.
哭泣是对疼痛的自然反应
Crying is a natural response to pain.
我没有要哭
I'm not crying.
-我会扫描你查看伤情  -别扫描我
- I will scan you for injuries. - Don't scan me.
-扫描完毕  -不可理喻
- Scan complete. - Unbelievable.
你没有受伤
You have sustained no injuries.
但是你的荷尔蒙和神经递质水平
However, your hormone and neurotransmitter levels
表明你在经历一些情绪波动
indicate that you are experiencing mood swings,
这在青春期很常见
common in adolescence.
诊断结果为青春期
Diagnosis, puberty.
什么
What?
好了  是时候缩回去了
Okay. Time to shrink now.
你会经历体毛的增加
You should expect an increase in body hair,
特别是在你的脸上  胸前  腋窝还有
especially on your face, chest, armpits, and...
谢谢你  够了
Thank you! That's enough.
你还会经历一些奇怪但很强烈的欲望
You may also experience strange and powerful new urges.
好了  回到你的箱子里去吧
Okay! Let's get you back in your luggage.
在你没对我的服务表示满意之前
I cannot deactivate until you say
我无法进入休眠
you are satisfied with your care.
好吧  我很满意我的...
Fine. I'm satisfied with my...
那是我的微型机器人吗
My microbot?
这没道理啊
This doesn't make any sense.
对于要过渡到成年阶段的青少年来说
Puberty can often be a confusing time
青春期通常是让人感到迷惑的
for a young adolescent flowering into manhood.
不  这东西应该被其它微型机器人吸引
No. The thing is attracted to the other microbots,
但那不可能
but that's impossible.
它们都在大火里被毁掉了
They were destroyed in the fire.
这个蠢东西坏掉了
Dumb thing's broken.
你的小机器人想要去哪里
Your tiny robot is trying to go somewhere.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
你干脆找一下它想去哪儿吧
Why don't you find out where it's trying to go?
那会稳定你青春期的情绪波动吗
Would that stabilize your pubescent mood swings?
当然了
Absolutely.
白球恩
Baymax?
搞什么
What?
-宏  -嘿  凯斯婶婶
- Hiro? - Hey, Aunt Cass!
你起来了  而且
Wow. You're up and...
是啊  我想是时候了
Yeah! I figured it was time.
你要去学校注册吗
Are you registering for school?
是的
Yes.
我考虑了你说的  确实启发了我
I thought about what you said. Really inspired me.
亲爱的  那太好了
Oh, honey, that's so great.
好了
Okay,
今晚给你准备特别大餐
special dinner tonight.
我会准备些鸡翅
I'll whip up some chicken wings.
涂上辣酱  辣到你脸都麻
You know, with the hot sauce that makes our faces numb.
-听起来不错  -就这么定了
- Okay, sounds good. - Great!
最后抱抱
Last hug.
白球恩
Baymax!
看路
Watch it!
白球恩
Baymax!
你疯了吗  你在干什么
Are you crazy? What are you doing?
我在找你的小机器人想去哪儿
I have found where your tiny robot wants to go.
我说过它坏掉了  它没想去...
I told you, it's broken. It's not trying to go...
锁上了
Locked.
那里有个窗户
There is a window.
请小心些
Please exercise caution.
从这个高度摔下会造成肢体损伤
A fall from this height could lead to bodily harm.
不好了
Oh, no.
稍等  我放些气出来
Excuse me while I let out some air.
你好了吗
Are you done?
是的
Yes.
重新充气还需要一会儿
It will take me a moment to re-inflate.
好吧  小点儿声就行
Fine, just keep it down.
这不是我的微型机器人吗
My microbots?
有人在大量生产
Someone's making more.
宏
Hiro?
你把我的心脏病都吓出来了
You gave me a heart attack!
我的双手可以用作除颤器  请离手
My hands are equipped with defibrillators. Clear.
停下  快停下  只是一种形容而已
Stop, stop, stop! It's just an expression.
不好了
Oh, no.
快跑
Run!
快点
Oh, come on!
我走不快
I am not fast.
果然没骗我
Yeah, no kidding!
快走  快点
Go! Go! Come on.
把门踢开
Kick it down!
那砸开
Then punch it!
快走  快走
Go! Go!
快点  快走
Oh, come on! Go, go, go!
快下去
Move it!
快点
Come on!
不  不
No, no.
快点儿  去窗户那里
Come on! The window!
快挤过去
Suck it in!
白球恩
Baymax!
宏
Hiro?
快  咱们快离开这儿
Come on, let's get out of here.
走  快点
Go! Hurry!
好吧  让我先搞清楚
All right, let me get this straight.
一个戴着歌舞伎面具的男人追杀你们
A man in a kabuki mask attacked you,
他还有一支微型飞行机器人大军
with an army of miniature flying robots.
是微型机器人
"Microbots."
-微型机器人  -对
-Microbots. -Yeah.
他利用神经传递器
He was controlling them
通过心灵感应来控制它们
telepathically with a neurocranial transmitter.
也就是说  这位歌舞伎先生
So, Mr. Kabuki was using esp
是在用超能力来追杀你和气球人
to attack you and balloon man.
你的飞行机器人被偷时你没来备案吗
Did you file a report when your flying robots were stolen?
没  我以为它们已经烧毁了
No. I thought they were all destroyed.
我知道这听着挺扯的
Look, I know it sounds crazy,
不过当时白球恩也在
but Baymax was there, too.
-和他讲讲  -好的  警官
-Tell him. -Yes, officer.
他说的是真...
He's telling the truth.
你这是...怎么了
What the... What's wrong with you?
电量低
Low battery.
你得挺住
Try to keep it together.
我是白球恩  你的个人医疗保健伙伴
I'm healthcare, your personal Baymax companion.
孩子  不如我给你父母打个电话
Kid, how about we call your parents,
叫他们来一趟好了
and get them down here?
什么
What?
把你的姓名和电话写在这儿
Write your name and number down
这样我们就可以...
on this piece of paper, and we can...
我得把你弄回家  放到充电座上
I've gotta get you home to your charging station.
你还能走吗
Can you walk?
我将对你进行扫描  扫描完毕
I will scan you now. Scan complete.
医疗保健
Healthcare.
好了
Okay.
我婶婶问起  就说整天在学校  懂吗
If my aunt asks, we were at school all day. Got it?
我们还跳窗户了呢
We jumped out a window.
别  小点声
No! Quiet!
我们还跳窗户了呢
We jumped out a window.
在凯斯婶婶面前可不能提那些事
You can't say things like that around aunt Cass.
宏
Hiro?
你回来了  亲爱的
You home, sweetie?
是啊
That's right.
我就说我听见你了嘛
I thought I heard you.
凯斯婶婶
Hey, aunt Cass.
看看我的小大学生
Look at my little college man.
我都等不急要听了
I can't wait to hear all about it!
鸡翅马上就好
And wings are almost ready.
哦耶
Whee!
你别出声
Will you be quiet?
是啊  鸡翅  哦耶
Yeah, wings! Whee!
好了  准备辣到你脸都麻了吗
All right, get ready to have your face melted.
吃完明天可就不好受了
We are gonna feel these things tomorrow.
懂我的意思吗
You know what I'm saying?
好了
Okay.
快坐下  给我讲讲
Sit down. Tell me everything.
问题是  我太晚去报到
The thing is that, since I registered so late,
所以还有好多事情要弄
I've got a lot of school stuff to catch up on.
什么动静
What was that?
摩奇
Mochi.
那该死的猫
That darn cat.
至少吃点再上去  好吗
At least take a plate for the road, okay?
-别学得太...-多谢关心
-Don't work too... -Thanks for understanding.
毛毛球  毛毛球
Hairy baby. Hairy baby.
好了  来吧
All right, come on.
我是医疗保健  你的个人白球恩伙伴
I'm healthcare, your personal baymax companion.
一只脚先迈进去
One foot in front of the other.
这没道理啊
This doesn't make any sense.
正
Tadashi.
什么
What?
正
Tadashi.
正走了
Tadashi's gone.
那他什么时候回来
When will he return?
他死了  白球恩
He's dead, baymax.
正身体很好啊
Tadashi was in excellent health.
合理饮食而且注重锻炼
With a proper diet and exercise,
应该活得很久才对
he should have lived a long life.
是啊  本该是的
Yeah, he should have.
可是一场大火...
But there was a fire and...
现在  他已经不在了
Now, he's gone.
-正在这里  -不
-Tadashi is here. -No.
人们总是说他没有真的离开
People keep saying he's not really gone.
只要我们还想着他
As long as we remember him.
就还是会疼
It still hurts.
你的身体上未发现有损伤
I see no evidence of physical injury.
那是另一种疼
It's a different kind of hurt.
你是我的患者
You are my patient.
我愿意帮忙
I would like to help.
这个你治不了  伙计
You can't fix this one, buddy.
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
我在下载有关于你的缺失数据
I am downloading a database on personal loss.
数据库下载完毕
Database downloaded.
治疗方法包括联系你的亲朋好友
Treatments include contact with friends and loved ones.
诊断
丧亲之痛
治疗方案
联系家人与朋友
我正在联系他们
I am contacting them now.
别  别  别联系他们
No, no, no! I... Don't do that.
已联系你的朋友
Your friends have been contacted.
真是的
Unbelievable.
你这是干嘛
Now, what are you doing?
其它治疗包括同情和肢体抚慰
Other treatments include compassion and physical reassurance.
我没事  真的
I'm okay. Really.
会好起来的  好了  好了
You will be all right. There, there.
谢谢  白球恩
Thanks, Baymax.
关于火灾的事我很遗憾
I am sorry about the fire.
没事啦  那是个意外
It's okay. It was an accident.
除非...
Unless...
除非那不是意外
Unless it wasn't.
在作品展上
At the showcase,
那个戴面具的家伙偷走我的微型机器人
that guy in the mask stole my microbots. And...
然后放火来掩人耳目
And then set the fire to cover his tracks.
他该对正的死负责
He's responsible for Tadashi.
我们得去抓住那家伙
We gotta catch that guy.
它是活的
It's alive!
它是活的  它是活的  它是活的
It's alive, it's alive! It's alive!
要想抓住他
If we're gonna catch that guy,
你得升升级
you need some upgrades.
抓住那个戴面具的男人
Will apprehending the man
会改善你的情绪状态吗
in the mask improve your emotional state?
当然会
Absolutely.
先改进一下你的身手
Let's work on your moves.
现在  来处理一下这里
Now, let's take care of this.
我有个疑虑
I have some concerns.
这盔甲可能会破坏掉我这无害抱抱的设计
This armor may undermine my non-threatening, huggable design.
要的就是这样  伙计
That's kind of the idea, buddy.
sick有不舒服之意
你帅惨了
You look sick.
我不可能不舒服  我是个机器人
I cannot be sick. I am a robot.
只是一种形容而已
It's just an expression.
数据转移完毕
Data transfer complete.
滨田正
我没觉得
I fail to see
空手道能让我成为更称职的医疗保健伙伴
how karate makes me a better healthcare companion.
你希望我健康  不是吗
You want to keep me healthy, don't you?
朝这儿打
Punch this.
太棒了  锤拳
Yes! Hammerfist!
侧踢
Side kick!
手刀
Knifehand!
后踢
Back kick!
小熊软糖
Gummy bears!
太好了
Yes!
来  顶个拳
Yeah! Fist bump!
我的搏击数据库没有顶拳这招
"Fist bump" Is not in my fighting database.
不  这个和搏击没关系
No, this isn't a fighting thing.
当人们兴奋或者是激动的时候
It's what people do sometimes
就会顶拳
when they're excited or pumped up.
看  这不就会了嘛
Hey, now you're getting it.
我会将"顶拳"添加到我的关爱矩阵中
I will add "Fist bump" to my care-giving matrix.
好了  我们去找那家伙吧
All right. Let's go get that guy.
快来
Come on!
拿下他  白球恩
Get him, Baymax!
我们来晚了
We're too late.
你的小机器人好像想去哪里
Your tiny robot is trying to go somewhere.
来
Come on.
建议饭后一小时再游泳
Always wait one hour after eating before swimming.
快跑
Come on!
你的心跳急剧加快...
Your heart rate has increased dramatic...
好了  白球恩  你升的级该派上用场了
Okay, Baymax, time to use those upgrades.
-宏  -不  别过来
-Hiro? -No, no, no!
离开这儿  快走
Get out of here! Go!
哥们  你在这干什么呢
Dude, what are you doing out here?
没干什么  就是随便走走
Nothing! Just out for a walk.
缓解一下青春期的情绪波动
Helps my pubescent mood swings.
那是白球恩吗
Is that Baymax?
是的  你们真不用...
Yeah, but you really...
他为什么穿着碳纤维内裤
Why is he wearing carbon fiber underpants?
我还会空手道呢
I also know karate.
你们得走了
You guys need to go.
别拒我们千里之外  宏
No, don't push us away, Hiro.
我们愿意帮你
We're here for you.
白球恩联系我们也是因为这个
That's why Baymax contacted us.
痛失至亲的人
Those who suffer a loss,
需要来自亲朋好友的支持
require support from friends and loved ones.
好吧  可我...
Okay, but I...
谁愿意跟我们先来分享他的感受
Who would like to share their feelings first?
我来
I'll go. Okay.
我叫弗雷迪  我快有三十天...
My name is Fred, and it has been 30 days since my last...
我的妈啊
Holy mother of megazon!
我是不是眼花了
Am I the only one seeing this?
老天爷  不要
Oh, my gosh! Oh, no!
快跑
Go!
抓住他  白球恩
Baymax, get him!
别  别  别  你这是干嘛
No, no, no, no, no! What are you doing?
我这是救你命
I'm saving your life.
白球恩能搞定他
Baymax can handle that guy!
不好了
Oh, no.
山葵
Wasabi!
拜拜
Goodbye!
宏  快说清楚  马上
Hiro. Explanation. Now.
他偷了我的微型机器人  还放了火
He stole my microbots. He started the fire.
我不知道他是谁
I don't know who he is!
白球恩  掌根推击
Baymax, palm-heel strike!
左转
Hard left!
看那面具  那身黑衣服
That mask, the black suit...
我们正在被超级大反派追杀  同志们
We're under attack from a super villain, people!
看  多酷
I mean, how cool is that?
确实是挺危险  不过  实在太酷了
I mean, it's scary, obviously. But how cool!
怎么停了
Why are we stopped?
红灯
The light's red!
追车戏哪来的红灯
There are no red lights in a car chase!
他为什么要杀我们
Why is he trying to kill us?
你为什么要杀我们
Why are you trying to kill us?
这种典型的反派看得多了
It's classic villain. We've seen too much!
我们别冒下结论
Let's not jump to conclusions.
没人说他要杀我们
We don't know he's trying to kill us.
小心
Car!
他是要杀我们
He's trying to kill us!
你刚刚是打转向灯了吗
Did you just put your blinker on?
你得表明你是要转弯啊
You have to indicate your turn!
要遵守交通规则
It's the law!
够了
That's it.
停车
Stop the car!
我和白球恩可以对付他
Baymax and I can take this guy!
时刻系好安全带
Seatbelts save lives.
安全才能时刻在
Buckle up, every time.
你干什么  你干什么
What are you doing? What are you doing?
-甩掉他了吗  -小心
-Did we lose him? -Look out!
白球恩  抓紧
Baymax, hold on!
-我们完了  -我们能行
-We're not gonna make it! -We're gonna make it!
成功了  耶
We made it! Yes!
我说了我们能行
I told you we'd make it!
你的伤口需要检查
Your injuries require my attention.
而且你的体温过低
And your body temperatures are low.
我们得赶紧离开
We should get out of here.
我知道个地方
I know a place.
这是哪儿
Where are we?
弗雷迪
Fred.
你这是去哪儿
Where are you going?
欢迎来到"米卡萨"
Welcome to mi casa.
"米卡萨"实际为西语而非法语
是法语里"前门"的意思
That's French for "Front door."
其实不是
It's really not.
听着  二货
Listen, nitwit.
刚刚才有个戴面具的疯子要杀我们
A lunatic in a mask just tried to kill us.
我可没心情...
I'm not in the mood for any...
欢迎回家  弗雷德里克少爷
Welcome home, master Frederick.
好哥们  希斯克里夫
Heathcliff, my man!
大伙快进来  在这儿会很安全
Come on in, guys. We'll be safe in here.
顶一个
Gimme some.
弗雷迪
Freddie,
这是你家
this is your house?
我以为你住在桥洞底下呢
I thought you lived under a bridge.
确切的说  是我父母的
Well, technically, it belongs to my parents.
他们正在我家的小岛上度假呢
They're on a vacay on the family island.
其实我们什么时候也该去一趟  好好玩玩
You know, we should totally go some time. Frolic.
你这是逗我呢
You gotta be kidding me.
弗雷迪  别碰我
要不是我刚刚被一个面具男追杀
If I wasn't just attacked by a guy in a kabuki mask,
这绝对是我今天见到的最不可思议的事
I think this would be the weirdest thing I've seen today.
简直看不下去了
My brain hates my eyes for seeing this.
你的体温仍然很低
Your body temperature is still low.
是啊
Yeah.
就像抱着一大块暖暖的棉花糖
It's like spooning a warm marshmallow.
真棒
It's so nice.
哦  又暖又舒服
Oh, yeah, that's toasty.
乖机器人
Good robot.
有人认识这个符号吗
Does this symbol mean anything to you guys?
-是只鸟  -不
-Yes! It's a bird! -No!
面具男拿的东西上
The guy in the mask was carrying something
有这个符号
with this symbol on it.
抓住那个戴面具的人
Apprehending the man in
会改善宏的情绪状态
the mask will improve Hiro's emotional state.
抓住他
Apprehend him?
我们都不知道他是谁
We don't even know who he is.
我有个想法
I have a theory.
"杀人狂博士"
"Dr. Slaughter, md"?
其实是身家百万的武器设计师
Actually, millionaire weapons designer,
马尔科姆·查兹提克
Malcolm chazzletick.
"歼灭者"
"The annihilator"?
真实身份  工业家雷德·阿克斯沃西
Behind the mask, industrialist Reid Axworthy.
"冯·破坏男爵"  直接说重点
"Baron Von destruct"? Just get to the point!
你们没明白吗
Don't you guys get it?
那个戴面具追杀我们的人
The man in the mask who attacked us
其实就是...
is none other than...
瞧
Voila!
阿里斯特·克瑞
Alistair krei.
-什么  -你想想
-What? -Think about it.
克瑞想要你的微型机器人  你不给
Krei wanted your microbots, and you said no.
但是像他这样的人不会就此善罢甘休
But rules don't apply to a man like krei.
不可能  他人这么高调
There's no way. The guy is too high profile.
那么那个人是谁
Then who was that guy in the mask?
我不知道
I don't know.
我们对他一无所知
We don't know anything about him.
那个人是AB型阴性血
His blood type is ab-negative.
-体内胆固醇含量...-白球恩
-Cholesterol levels are... - Baymax,
你扫描他了
you scanned him?
程序设定要求我评估每个人的健康需求
I am programed to assess everyone's healthcare needs.
太棒了
Yes!
我用这个数据就能把他揪出来了
I can use the data from your scan to find him.
所以你是打算花一辈子的时间
You'd have to scan everyone in San fransokyo.
来扫描旧京山的每个人
That might take, I don't know, forever.
不  不  不  我...
No, no, no, no. I...
我只是需要换个角度来思考
I just have to look for another angle.
有了
Got it!
只要升级了白球恩的传感器
I'll scan the whole city at the same time.
我就能一次性扫描全城的人
I just have to upgrade Baymax's sensor.
事实上  要想抓住那家伙
Actually, if we're gonna catch this guy,
你们都得来次大改造
I need to upgrade all of you.
你说改造谁
Upgrade who, now?
痛失至亲的人
Those who suffer a loss
需要来自亲朋好友的支持
require support from friends and loved ones.
这个节奏我喜欢
Okay, I like where this is heading!
我们这群书呆子可对付不了那家伙
We can't go against that guy! We're nerds!
宏  我们很想帮你
Hiro, we want to help,
可我们就只是我们
but we're just us.
不
No.
你们的能耐可不止这些
You can be way more.
滨田正是我们的挚友
Tadashi Hamada was our best friend.
就听你的了
We're in.
你们有这种感觉吗  伙计们
Can you feel it? You guys, do you feel this?
我们即将书写自己的故事
Our origin story begins.
我们就要成为超级英雄了
We're gonna be superheroes!
手抬起来
Arms up.
神经传递器一定藏在他面具里
The neurotransmitter must be in his mask.
面具一旦到手  他就没辙了
We get the mask, and he can't control the bots.
游戏结束
Game over.
旁人笑我太平凡
They say "We are what we are"
可不必就此认命
But we don't have to be
我举止乖张
I'm bad behavior
可我仍会倾尽全力
But I do it in the best way
永恒之火熊熊燃烧
I'll be the watcher
我将静观其变
Of the eternal flame
你们狂热的梦想
I'll be the guard dog
由我来保驾护航
Of all your fever dreams
我就是那沙漏底部的点点细砂
I am the sand in the bottom half of the hourglass
因为我们终将成为不朽
Cause we could be immortals
成为不朽
Immortals
就在不久之后
Just not for long for long
放下过去种种恩怨
Live with me forever now
携手并进共同向前
Pull the blackout curtains down
就在不久之后
Just not for long for long
我们终将成为不朽
We could be immortals
成为不朽
Immortals
有时心存信仰的唯一回报
Sometimes the only payoff for having any faith
源于历经重重考验后仍在我心
Is when it's tested again and again every day
我依旧将你的过去比作我的未来
I'm still comparing your past to my future
因为我们终将成为不朽
Cause we could be immortals
成为不朽
Immortals
就在不久之后
Just not for long for long
超级弹跳
Super jump!
放下过去种种恩怨
Pull the blackout curtains down
-我能喷火啦  -就在不久之后
-I breathe fire. -Just not for long for long
我们终将成为不朽
We could be immortals
载入史诗
Immortals
书写传奇
成为不朽
Immortals
我爱死这身了
I love it!
还行吧
Not bad.
你们的衣服都很合身吗
Anybody else's suit riding up on them?
伙计们
Hey, guys!
来看看这个
Check this out.
很荣幸为你们介绍
I'd like to introduce,
二代白球恩
Baymax 2.0.
帅呆了
He's glorious.
好啦  集中注意力
Hold up. Focus.
给他们露一手  老兄
Show 'em what you got, buddy.
拳头啊  让他们见识下那个拳头
The fist, show them the fist.
不  不是这个
No, not that.
是那个  另外那个
The thing, the other thing.
火箭飞拳让弗雷迪开心极了
Rocket fist make Freddie so happy!
新特性还不止这个
That's just one of his new upgrades!
白球恩  展开双翼
Baymax, wings.
不是吧
No way!
推进器准备
Thrusters.
我没觉得飞行
I fail to see how flying
能让我成为更称职的医疗保健伙伴
makes me a better healthcare companion.
我更不明白你为什么不觉得这个赞爆了
I fail to see how you fail to see that it's awesome!
全速推进
Full thrust.
稳住了  大块头
Steady, big guy.
不着急  慢慢来
Look, let's just take this slow.
起来  起来  起来
Up, up, up, up, up!
向上推进  向上推进
Thrust, thrust, thrust!
过头了  过头了
Too much thrust! Too much thrust!
推进过头了
Too much thrust!
不  不  不  不
No, no, no, no!
别熄火  别熄火
Back on! Back on!
别  别  别
On! On! On!
起来  起来  起来
Go up! Up, up, up!
我的天
Oh, man!
今天算是飞够了
Maybe... Maybe enough flying for today.
你说呢
What do you say?
你的神经递质激素水平正稳步上升
Your neurotransmitter levels are rising steadily.
这说明什么
Which means what?
刚才的治疗见效了
The treatment is working.
不
Oh, no!
不  不  不  不  不
No, no, no, no, no!
别这样  白球恩
Whoa, Baymax!
太棒了
Yes!
这真是...
That was...
真是...
酷毙了
Sick.
只是一种形容而已
It is just an expression.
你说得对  伙计
That's... that's right, buddy.
我再也不想坐公交了
I am never taking the bus again.
你的情绪状态有所好转
Your emotional state has improved.
只要你对服务表示满意  我随时能休眠
I can deactivate if you say you are satisfied with your care.
什么
What?
我才不想你休眠
No, I don't want you to deactivate.
我们还没找到那家伙呢
We still have to find that guy.
好了  启动超级传感器吧
So, fire up that super-sensor.
扫描功能已强化
Functionality improved.
搜寻范围扩大十倍
1000% increase in range.
已找到匹配源
I have found a match,
就在那座岛上
on that island.
-风景还不错  -是啊  如果...
-Killer view. -Yeah. If I...
如果我不恐高的话
If I wasn't terrified of heights,
我应该会喜欢这个
I'd probably love this.
可是我很恐高  所以我一点都不喜欢
But I'm terrified of heights, so I don't love it.
在那儿  白球恩  带我们过去
There. Baymax, take us in.
棒极了
Awesome!
作战小分队的首次着陆
Our first landing together as a team.
走吧  伙计们
Guys, come on.
"隔离区"
"Quarantine"?
你们不会不知道"隔离"是什么意思吧
Do you people know what "Quarantine" Means?
"隔离"
"Quarantine."
是为了防止污染物引起疾病甚至死亡
Enforced isolation to prevent contamination
所采取的一种强制性隔绝手段
that could lead to disease, or, in some cases, death.
标志牌上可有个骷髅头
There's a skull face on this one.
那可是骷髅头
A skull face!
别放松警惕
Be ready.
他说不定就在附近
He could be anywhere.
受死吧
Fire!
烧死你  烧死你
Spitting fire! Spitting fire!
只是一只鸟
That was a bird.
至少我们的装备挺管用的
Well, at least we know our gear works.
锵锵六人行
Six intrepid friends
弗雷迪是老大
Led by Fred
老大是弗雷迪
Their leader, Fred
弗雷迪的守护者们
Fred's angels
手持阁楼捡来的古老护身符
Harnessing the power of the sun with the
随意驾驭太阳的力量
Ancient amulet they found in the attic
护身符是绿的
The amulet is green
说不定是祖母绿
It's probably an emerald
弗雷迪  再唱信不信我劈你脸上
Fred, I will laser-hand you in the face.
伙计们  别出声
Guys, Shhhh...
有发现他的踪迹吗  白球恩
Any sign of him, Baymax?
这幢建筑干扰了我的传感器
This structure is interfering with my sensor.
棒极了  机器人罢工了
Perfect. The robot's broken.
伙计们  你们可能想看看这个
Guys, you might want to see this.
你觉得这是什么  天才
What do you think it is, genius?
我不确定  可是看那个
I'm not sure. But look.
宏
Hiro.
克瑞
Krei.
这就对了
That's right.
我们的使命就是挑战不可能
We were asked to do the impossible.
这就是我们的成果
That's what we did.
重新定义传输真正的概念
We've reinvented the very concept of transportation.
朋友们  这就是寂静雀计划
Friends, I present project Silent Sparrow.
长官  借用一下
General, may I?
魔法帽
Magic hat!
隐形传输
Teleportation.
物体通过隐形空间实现实时传送
The transport of matter instantaneously through space.
再也不只是科幻小说的情节了
Not science fiction anymore.
不过我们斥巨资可不仅仅是为了运送帽子
Now, we didn't spend billions of tax dollars to teleport hats.
女士们先生们  你们即将见证历史
Ladies and gentlemen, you're here to witness history.
准备好兜风了吗  艾比盖尔
Ready to go for a ride, Abigail?
既然请到了这么多人
We've invited all these people.
那就让他们都开开眼界
Might as well give 'em a show.
发射前倒计时三十秒
T-minus 30 seconds to launch.
-29  28  -阿尔戈号
-29, 28... -This is argo.
-舱体就位  -27...
-Capsule's in position. -27...
先生  我们刚刚检测到
Sir, we've picked up a slight irregularity
磁控场出现了小范围的异常波动
in the magnetic containment field.
克瑞先生  出什么问题了吗
Mr. Krei, is there a problem?
不  当然没问题
No. No problem.
安全范围内的参数浮动罢了
It's well within the parameters.
我们继续
Let's move forward.
三  二  一
3, 2, 1.
座舱气压正常
Cabin pressure is go.
机舱发射
Pod engaged.
磁场破裂  立刻停止
Field breach! Abort!
我们和机舱失去联系了
We've lost all contact with the pod.
不  天啊
Oh, no.
-传送门在解体  -飞行员失踪了
-It's breaking up! -The pilot is gone.
二号传送门已失效
Portal two is down.
磁控场也失效了
The magnetic containment field's down!
克瑞  马上关掉它
Krei, shut it down now!
封闭全岛  禁止进入
I want this island sealed off!
政府叫停了克瑞的项目
The government shut down Krei's experiment.
所以他想用你的微型机器人把机器偷回来
And he's using your microbots to steal his machine back.
克瑞真的是那个面具男
Krei is the guy in the mask.
不好了
Oh, no.
白球恩  带我们离开这
Baymax, get us out of here.
去抢传递器
Go for the transmitter.
就在面具后面
Behind his mask.
白球恩
Baymax!
好了  计划是什么
All right, what's the plan?
该弗雷迪出场了
It's Fred time.
超级弹跳
Super jump!
重力摧毁
Gravity crush!
急速坠落
Falling hard.
说真的  计划是什么
Seriously, what is the plan?
-抢面具  -我做你的后盾
-Get the mask. -Right behind you.
开什么玩笑  计划到底是什么
For real, what is the plan?
你
Hey!
想跳舞吗  面具男
You want to dance, masked man?
要不就和这个来一曲吧
'Cause you'll be dancing with these.
乖乖交出面具  否则让你尝尝这个
Hand over the mask, or you'll get a taste of this!
还有这个
And a little bit of that!
我干得还不错
Hey! I did all right.
你就这点能耐吗
Is that all you got?
还有这一手啊
You got that, too?
看我不烧死你
It's back into the fire!
你完了  克瑞
It's over, Krei.
教...  卡拉翰教授
Pro... Professor Callaghan?
那场爆炸...
The explosion...
你明明死了
You died.
没死  幸亏你的微型机器人
No. I had your microbots.
可是  正
But, Tadashi.
你就眼看着他送死
You just let him die.
把面具给我  宏
Give me the mask, Hiro.
他冲进去是为了救你
He went in there to save you!
那是他自己太冲动了
That was his mistake!
白球恩  干掉他
Baymax, destroy.
我的程序设定不允许我伤害人类
My programing prevents me from injuring a human being.
不再是了
Not anymore.
宏  这不是...
Hiro, this is not what...
去吧  白球恩  干掉他
Do it, Baymax! Destroy him!
不  住手  白球恩
No! Stop, Baymax!
不  快放手  他要跑了
No, stop! He's getting away!
白球恩
Baymax!
我违反了程序设定的健康协议
My healthcare protocol has been violated.
很抱歉对你们造成了伤害
I regret any distress I may have caused.
你们怎么能这样  我都抓住他了
How could you do that? I had him!
你刚刚做的事  我们可没事先说好
What you just did, we never signed up for.
我们只说好抓住他
We said we'd catch the guy.
仅此而已
That's it.
我就不该让你们帮我
I never should have let you help me!
白球恩  定位卡拉翰
Baymax, find Callaghan.
强化扫描仪故障了
My enhanced scanner has been damaged.
展开双翼
Wings.
宏  这不是计划的一部分
Hiro, this isn't part of the plan.
起飞
Fly!
宏
Hiro!
你的血压升高了
Your blood pressure is elevated.
表明你正处于烦恼中
You appear to be distressed.
我没事
I'm fine!
好了  能用了吗
There. Is it working?
-传感器工作正常  -很好
- My sensor is operational. - Good.
那就去
Then let's get...
搞什么
What?
你要移除我的医疗芯片吗
Are you going to remove my healthcare chip?
是的  快打开
Yes. Open!
我的设计初衷是治愈疾病和伤痛
My purpose is to heal the sick and injured.
白球恩  打开你的芯片槽
Baymax, open your access port.
你要我终结卡拉翰教授吗
Do you want me to terminate Professor Callaghan?
快打开它
Just open!
终结卡拉翰教授
Will terminating Professor Callaghan
就能平复你的情绪吗
improve your emotional state?
没错  不  我不知道
Yes! No! I don't know!
快开启芯片槽
Open your access!
-这是正想看到的吗  -不重要
- Is this what Tadashi wanted? - It doesn't matter!
正的设计初衷旨在帮助他人并...
Tadashi programed me to aid and...
正死了
Tadashi's gone!
正已经不在了
Tadashi's gone.
正在这儿
Tadashi is here.
不  他已经不在了
No. He's not here.
正还在这儿
Tadashi is here.
我是滨田正
This is Tadashi Hamada.
这是我机器人项目的第一次测试
And this is the first test of my robotics project.
你好  我是白球恩
Hello, I am Baymax.
停下  停下  快停下
Stop! Stop! Stop! Stop! Stop! Stop!
机器人项目第七次测试
The seventh test of my robotics project.
你好  我...
Hello, I...
搞什么
What? What?
等等  停下  停止扫描  停...
Wait, wait, wait, stop! Stop scan! Stop...
还是我  滨田正
Tadashi Hamada again,
这是我项目的第三十三次测试
and this is the 33rd test of my robotics project.
我不会放弃你的
I'm not giving up on you.
你可能还不明白  但是人们会需要你的
You don't understand this yet, but people need you.
咱们继续努力吧
So, let's get back to work.
我是滨田正
This is Tadashi Hamada,
这是第八十四次测试
and this is the 84th test.
准备好了吗  大家伙
What do you say, big guy?
你好  我是白球恩
Hello, I am Baymax,
你的个人医疗保健伙伴
your personal healthcare companion.
成功了
It works.
It works!
太棒了  竟然...成功了
This is amazing! You... you work!
我就知道能行
I knew it! I knew it! I knew it.
我就知道  会成功的  难以置信
I knew it. Oh, you work. I can't believe it! I can't...
好吧  最关键的一步
Okay. All right, big moment, here.
扫描我
Scan me.
你的神经传递素明显增多
Your neurotransmitter levels are elevated.
表明你现在十分开心
This indicates that you are happy.
是的  超级开心
I am. I really am.
天啊  我得带我弟来看看
Oh, man. Wait till my brother sees you.
你一定能帮助很多人  伙计
You're gonna help so many people, buddy.
很多很多人
So many.
先这样吧  我很满意你的服务
That's all for now. I am satisfied with my care.
谢谢你  白球恩
Thank you, Baymax.
真抱歉
I'm so sorry.
我一点也赶不上我哥哥
I guess I'm not like my brother.
宏
Hiro.
伙计们  我...
Guys, I, I...
我们一起去阻止卡拉翰
We're going to catch Callaghan,
这次一定不会搞砸
and, this time, we'll do it right.
下次可别再把你的队友
But maybe don't leave your team
丢在阴森森的岛上了
stranded on a spooky island next time.
-抱歉  -没关系
- Oh, man. - Nah, it's cool.
希斯克里夫开直升机把我们接来的
Heathcliff picked us up in the family chopper.
宏  你得看看这个
Hiro, we found something you should see.
你差点害死我们
You almost got us all killed!
克瑞  都怪你
Krei! You did this!
你早知道计划还不完善
You knew it wasn't ready!
卡拉翰  他怎么也在
Callaghan? He was there?
他本是个好人啊  发生了什么
He was such a good man. What happened?
不知道
I don't know.
答案一定藏在某处
But the answer's here somewhere.
等等  暂停
Wait, wait! Stop.
他在那儿
There he is.
和飞行员一起
With the pilot.
等等
Hang on.
既然请来了这么多人...
We've invited all these people...
卡拉翰
飞行员是卡拉翰的女儿
The pilot was Callaghan's daughter.
所以卡拉翰才怪罪于克瑞
Callaghan blames Krei.
他要为女儿复仇
This is a revenge story.
还等什么
So, what are we waiting for?
都布置好了
It's all set up.
这美丽的新园区是我毕生梦想的至高点
This beautiful new campus is the culmination of a lifelong dream.
感谢人生路上遇到的绊脚石
But none of this would've been possible
不然我也不会站在这
without a few bumps in the road.
这些障碍使我们变得更加强壮
Those setbacks made us stronger,
克瑞高科技工业园
并引领我们走向光明的未来
and set us on the path to a bright future.
那是什么
What is that?
-什么  -障碍
- What? - Setback?
我女儿在你眼中只是"障碍"吗
Was my daughter a "Setback"?
卡拉翰  你不是...
Callaghan! But you...
你女儿那是...
Your daughter, that...
那是个意外
That was an accident.
不  你明知那个实验很危险
No! You knew it was unsafe.
我女儿就是因你的自大而丧生的
My daughter is gone because of your arrogance.
你要干什么
What are you doing?
你将艾比盖尔送进机舱时
You took everything from me
便已夺走了我的一切
when you sent Abigail into that machine.
现在我要以牙还牙
Now I'm taking everything from you.
不
No!
不  不  别这样
No! No! You can't!
你所有的成就将在你面前消失殆尽
You're going to watch everything you've built disappear.
然后就轮到你
Then, it's your turn.
卡拉翰教授
Professor Callaghan!
放开他
Let him go!
这是艾比盖尔希望看到的吗
Is this what Abigail would've wanted?
艾比盖尔已经不在了
Abigail is gone!
这么做于事无补  相信我  我也经历过
This won't change anything. Trust me, I know.
这孩子说得没错  卡拉翰
Listen to the kid, Callaghan.
求你放了我吧
Please, let me go.
你要什么我都给你
I'll give you anything you want!
我要我女儿回来
I want my daughter back!
击落他的面具
Go for the mask!
白球恩
Baymax!
作战开始
Leaping into action!
不好
Oh, no!
这下压力有点大
Getting a little... A little tight.
-不妙  -他太强大了
- No! - He's too strong!
-我出不去了  -根本赢不了
- There's no way out! - You can't beat him!
救命  我斗不过他
Help! I can't beat him.
宏
Hiro!
-宏  宏  -救命
- Hiro? Hiro? - Help!
-对了  -宏
- That's it! - Hiro.
-我知道怎么战胜他了  -宏
- I know how to beat him. - Hiro.
听好了
Listen up!
动动你们的脑子
Use those big brains of yours,
把思路打开
and think your way around the problem.
换个新角度
Look for a new angle.
我的胳膊  再扯就断了
My arms! They can't go any further!
等一下  这是个外套
Wait a second, it's a suit.
你好啊  铁片
Hello, sign.
介意让我转一下吗
Care to go for a little spin?
二连转
Double spin!
背转式
Behind-the-back spin!
白球恩
Baymax!
宏
Hiro.
我爱死那个机器人了
I love that robot!
好了  新计划  别管面具了
Okay, new plan. Forget the mask.
先对付微型机器人  把它们弄进传送门
Take out the bots. They'll get sucked up into the portal.
这才叫计划
Now that is a plan!
小蜜  弗雷迪  能作掩护吗
Honey, Fred, can you give us some cover?
还用你说
Like you have to ask.
行动吧  弗雷迪
Let's do this, Freddie!
烟幕弹
Smokescreen!
预备
Ready and
俯冲
dive!
这边的重力有点异常  伙计们
Whoa, the gravity's getting a little weird here, guys!
正好将计就计
Wait. Let's use this!
尝尝充满怒火的绿刃吧
These are green blades of fury!
女人雄起
Woman up!
双牌花式
Double sign-spin.
老子的铁片热力四射
Now my signs are on fire!
这才叫化学反应
Now that's a chemical reaction!
后踢  手刀  回旋踢
Back kick. Knifehand. Roundhouse.
劈拳
Hammerfist.
你们完了
This ends now!
看来微型机器人不够用了
Looks like you're out of microbots.
什么
What?
白球恩
Baymax!
不
No!
程序设定不允许我们伤害人类
Our programing prevents us from injuring a human being.
不过这个归我们了
But we'll take that.
它仍在运行  我们得关闭它
It's still on! We have to shut it down!
办不到  遏制场正在失效
We can't! The containment field is failing.
传送门会自己销毁
The portal is gonna tear itself apart!
我们必须马上离开这儿
We need to get out of here, now!
白球恩
Baymax!
传感器检测到了生命迹象
My sensor is detecting signs of life.
-什么  -从那里面传出来的
- What? - Coming from there.
是女性的生命体征
The life signs are female.
她正处于深度休眠中
She appears to be in hyper-sleep.
是卡拉翰的女儿  她还活着
Callaghan's daughter. She's still alive.
艾比盖尔
Abigail.
我们去接她回来
Let's go get her.
传送门正在解体  你们做不到的
The portal is destabilizing. You'll never make it.
她还活着
She's alive in there.
总得有人去救她
Someone has to help.
你说呢  伙计
What do you say, buddy?
飞行确实让我成为更称职的医疗保健伙伴
Flying makes me a better healthcare companion.
小心  这里到处都是碎片
Careful! There's Krei tech debris everywhere.
小心
Look out!
已定位到患者
I have located the patient.
快去
Hurry!
来吧  伙计  带她回家
Come on, buddy, let's get her home.
我来指路  出发
I'll guide you out of here. Let's go!
右转
Veer right!
好的  朝左飞
Okay, to the left.
右急转弯
Hard right!
向上穿过去
Up and over.
好的  稳定向前  稳一点
Okay, level off. Easy.
飞得好
Nice flying!
就快到了
Almost there!
白球恩
Baymax!
推进器失灵了
My thrusters are inoperable.
抓住我的手
Just grab hold.
还有一种办法能让你们安全逃生
There is still a way I can get you both to safety.
在你没对我的服务表示满意之前
I cannot deactivate until you say
我无法进入休眠
you are satisfied with your care.
不  不  不  等等  你怎么办
No, no, no, no. Wait. What about you?
-你是我的患者  -白球恩
- You are my patient. - Baymax.
我只在乎你的安危
Your health is my only concern.
别说了  我会想出办法
Stop! I'm gonna figure out...
你对我的服务满意吗
Are you satisfied with your care?
不  肯定还有别的办法的
No. There's gotta be another way.
我不会把你丢下的  我会想出办法来的
I'm not gonna leave you here. I'll think of something.
没时间了
There is no time.
你对我的服务满意吗
Are you satisfied with your care?
求你了  别走
Please! No.
我不能再失去你
I can't lose you, too.
宏  我会一直陪在你身边
Hiro, I will always be with you.
我很满意你的服务
I'm satisfied with my care.
宏
Hiro!
太好了  他们成功了
Yeah! They made it!
白球恩呢
Baymax?
小姐  能听见吗
Miss, can you hear me?
你还记得自己的名字吗
What is your name?
艾比盖尔·卡拉翰
Abigail Callaghan.
好的  艾比盖尔  你会没事的
Okay, Abigail, you are gonna be fine.
我们这就送你去医院
We're taking you to the hospital.
过来
Move it!
进去
Get in there.
今天克瑞科技工业的总部
A massive cleanup continues today
仍在进行大量的清理工作
at the headquarters of Krei Tech Industries.
机器人学教授罗伯特·卡拉翰由于涉嫌摧毁克瑞科技园区而被拘留
有关神秘团体
Reports are still flooding in
阻止灾难发生的报导
about a group of unidentified individuals,
也如潮水般发布开来
who prevented what could have been a major catastrophe.
整个旧京山都在疑惑
The whole city of San Fransokyo is asking,
"这些英雄到底是谁  他们现在在何处"
"Who are these heroes? And where are they now?"
真是激动人心
It's so exciting.
亲爱的
Hey, sweetie!
好了
Okay.
再抱一下
Last hug.
再见
Bye!
-然后我就像...-一边儿去
- And just then I was like... - Get out of here.
我是白球恩  你的个人医疗保健伙伴
I am Baymax, your personal healthcare companion.
你好  宏
Hello, Hiro.
我们并非天生就是超级英雄
We didn't set out to be superheroes,
但生活不总会按照计划进行
but sometimes life doesn't go the way you planned.
好消息是  我哥哥希望能帮助更多的人
The good thing is, my brother wanted to help a lot of people,
这也是我们所要做的
and that's what we're gonna do.
我们是谁
Who are we?
超能
陆战队
片尾有彩蛋
老爸  真希望能和你分享我的成就
Dad, I just wish I could share my accomplishments with you.
你对我真的很重要  而且老实说
You mean so much to me, and honestly,
你总待在那个岛上
I've always felt a distance
咱俩之间都有隔阂了
what with you being on the family island all the time,
我只希望你能看看...
and I just wish you could see how...
弗雷迪
Fred.
儿子
Son.
老爸
Dad?
正面穿完反面穿
I wear 'em front, I wear 'em back.
脏了翻面还能穿
I go inside out, then I go front and back.
老爸
Dad!
看来咱爷俩有得聊了
We have a lot to talk about.
翻译  艾瑞卡  ellaxinxin
翻译  想吃锅巴  莱吉
翻译  牛奶器
校对  脸盆王子  somehacker
后期  8T     总监  somehacker
@懒死放映室 团队译制